<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>2012 FFF</title>
	<atom:link href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012</link>
	<description>The Best Indie Fest on Lake Pepin</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 04:40:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.8.6</generator>
	<item>
		<title>2012 Official Selections</title>
		<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/2012-official-selections/</link>
		<comments>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/2012-official-selections/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2012 04:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flywayfilmfestival.org/?p=23537</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[2012 2012 Flyway Film Festival Announces Official Film Selections • Documentary &#8220;Journey to Planet X&#8221; to Kick Off Festival • &#8220;Janeane From Des Moines&#8221; Selected for Closing Night • Exclusive Friday Late-Night Shorts Screening Today, the 2012 Flyway Film Festival officially announced the official selections for the 2012 2012 Flyway Film Festival. The Festival will [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>2012 2012 Flyway Film Festival Announces <a title="Flyway 2012 Films" href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/films/">Official Film Selections</a></p>
<p>• Documentary &#8220;<a title="Journey To Planet X" href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/film/journey-to-planet-x/"><em>Journey to Planet X</em></a>&#8221; to Kick Off Festival<br />
• &#8220;<a title="Janeane from Des Moines" href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/film/janeane-from-des-moines/"><em>Janeane From Des Moines</em></a>&#8221; Selected for Closing Night<br />
• Exclusive Friday Late-Night Shorts Screening</p>
<p>Today, the 2012 Flyway Film Festival officially announced the official selections for the 2012 2012 Flyway Film Festival. The Festival will run from Thursday, October 18 to Sunday, October 21 in Pepin and Stockholm, Wisconsin at the Lake Pepin Art &amp; Design Center and the Widespot Performing Arts Center. Now in its fifth year, the Festival has gained a reputation as a world-class event, showcasing the best in new local, regional, and international film and providing the movie-loving public with access to critically acclaimed filmmakers and film industry professionals from around the world.</p>
<p>The 2012 2012 Flyway Film Festival will screen over 35 feature films and shorts, representing 5 countries. This year, the Festival received more than 850 submissions from filmmakers around the world, an increase from 2011.<br />
<span id="more-23537"></span><br />
&#8220;Even thought this is our fifth year, it’s really a different Festival each time. The quality of entries was amazing this year and our advertising has never better,&#8221; said Executive Director Rick Vaicius. With the help of a 2012 Joint Effort Marketing (JEM) Grant from the Wisconsin Department of Tourism and Bolster Creative, Twin Cities Comcast watchers will soon see the 2012 Festival ad spots airing on a variety of channels.</p>
<p><em>Journey to Planet X</em> will kick off the Festival on October 18 at the Widespot Performing Arts Center in Stockholm. Directed by Myles Kane and Josh Khoury, this documentary follows friends and scientists-by-day/amateur-filmmakers-by-night Eric Swain and Troy Bernier during the trials and tribulations of making of their most ambitious sci-fi endeavor to date and sheds light on their unique brand of “movie magic.” This feature is paired with <em>Dinner at the Lake</em>, a community short film project of the 2012 Flyway Film Festival. Directors Louis Fisher (Stockholm, WI) and Griffin Larson (Minneapolis, MN) bring to life an ominous little tale by celebrated mystery author Mary Logue with a cast comprised of talented residents from along Lake Pepin’s eastern shore.</p>
<p>In addition, the Festival will host an exclusive “Friday Night Shorts” screening at the Lake Pepin Art &amp; Design Center that will include Damian Horan’s acclaimed student film, <em>Children of the Air</em> (USA), as well as offerings from Flyway alumni John Roberts (<em>The Wheel</em> – Wisconsin, USA), Jay Cheel (<em>The Politics of Competitive Board Gaming Amongst Friends</em> – Ontario, Canada), and Phillipe Lupien and Vincent Ethier (<em>Punchy &amp; Toothpick</em> – Montreal, Canada), among other selections.</p>
<p>All are welcome to attend the free, family-friendly <a title="Kids Shorts 2012" href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/film/kids-shorts/">Kids Shorts</a> programming block screening on Saturday morning at the Lake Pepin Art &amp; Design Center.</p>
<p>The politically timely mockumentary <em>Janeane From Des Moines</em> will close the Festival on October 21 at the Widespot Performing Arts Center. Directed by Grace Lee, native of Missouri, Janeane takes her audience on a journey with an &#8220;ordinary&#8221; woman who offers us an insider&#8217;s look at the American heartland&#8217;s ultra-right-wing movement.</p>
<p><strong>Opening Night Film:</strong><br />
• <em>Journey to Planet X</em>, Myles Kane and Josh Khoury (USA)<br />
shows with <em>Dinner at the Lake</em>, Louis Fisher (Wisconsin) and Griffin Larson (Minnesota)</p>
<p><strong>Closing Night Film:</strong><br />
• <em>Janeane From Des Moines</em>, Grace Lee (USA)<br />
shows with <em>Man on the Bluff</em>, Ben Vinar (USA)</p>
<p><strong>Friday Night Shorts:</strong><br />
• <em>Vivienne Again</em>, Kim Garland (USA)<br />
• <em>The Wheel</em>, John Roberts (USA)<br />
• <em>Children of the Air</em>, Damian Horan (USA)<br />
• <em>Punchy and Toothpick</em>, Philippe Lupien and Vincent Ethier (Canada)<br />
• <em>Happy Voodoo</em>, Jenny Goddard (USA)<br />
• <em>Looking Past You</em>, Jennifer Kramer (USA)<br />
• <em>The Politics of Competitive Board Gaming Amongst Friends</em>, Jay Cheel (Canada)</p>
<p><strong>Wisconsin/Minnesota Showcase:</strong><br />
• <em>The Wheel</em>, John Roberts (Wisconsin)<br />
• <em>Looking Past You</em>, Jennifer Kramer (Minnesota)</p>
<p><strong>Family-Friendly</strong><br />
• <em>Kids Shorts</em>, Various Free Admission</p>
<p><strong>Documentaries:</strong><br />
• <em>The Price of Sand</em>, Jim Tittle (USA) Screening as a Work in Progress<br />
• <em>Last Day at Lambeau</em>, Michael Neelson (USA)<br />
• <em>We’re Not Broke</em>, Karin Hayes and Victoria Bruce (USA)<br />
• <em>As Goes Janesville</em>, Brad Lichtenstein (USA)<br />
shows with <em>Invested: The Story of Three Youth Social Entrepreneurs</em>, Dawn Mikkelson (USA)<br />
• <em>Dreams of a Life</em>, Carol Morley (UK)<br />
• <em>Plimpton</em>, Tome Bean and Luke Poling (USA)<br />
• <em>Janeane From Des Moines</em>, Grace Lee (USA)<br />
shows with <em>Man on the Bluff</em>, Ben Vinar (USA)</p>
<p><strong>Narratives:</strong><br />
• <em>Teddy Bear</em>, Mads Matthiesen (Denmark) Not For Children<br />
• <em>Marvin, Seth, Stanley</em>, Steven Gurewitz (USA)<br />
shows with <em>Bridges</em>, Chris Bell (USA)<br />
• <em>How Do You Write a Joe Schermann Song</em>, Gary King (USA)<br />
• <em>Red Flag</em>, Alex Karpovsky (USA)<br />
shows with <em>Crush</em>, Rebecca Pugh (USA)<br />
• <em>Caroline and Jackie</em>, Adam Christian Clark (USA)<br />
shows with <em>Hellion</em>, Kat Candler (USA)<br />
• <em>L.A. Comedy Shorts Programming Block</em>, Various (USA)<br />
• <em>Supporting Characters</em>, Daniel Schechter (USA)<br />
• <em>La Sirga</em>, William Vega (Columbia)<br />
• <em>Pilgrim Song</em>, Martha Stephens (USA)<br />
• <em>Now Forager</em>, Jason Cortlund and Julia Halperin (USA)<br />
shows with <em>Planet X: The Frozen Moon</em>, Troy Bernier and Eric Swain (USA)<br />
• <em>The Sound of Small Things</em>, Peter McLarnan (USA)</p>
<p><em><strong>About the 2012 Flyway Film Festival</strong></em><br />
The 2012 2012 Flyway Film Festival runs October 18–21 in Pepin and Stockholm, Wisconsin. Over 35 national and international independent films will be shown in two venues, with many filmmakers and other industry professionals in attendance to interact with audiences via Q&amp;A and other social networking events.</p>
<p>Regular screening and full festival passes, which will include the Opening Night Gala and access to the Festival Lounge at the Breakwater, are available online now at flywayfilmfestival.org. Individual tickets are available online now and will also be available during the Festival at the Festival and Venue Box Offices.</p>
<p>Pepin and Stockholm are a 60-minute ride from Rochester, Minnesota or Eau Claire, Wisconsin and 90 minutes from the Minneapolis-St. Paul International Airport.</p>
<p>Flyway sprang from the monthly film programming and semi-annual filmmaker events curated by <a title="Bios" href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/bios/">Rick Vaicius</a> at the Lake Pepin Art &amp; Design Center in Pepin, Wisconsin in 2006.</p>
<p>Over the past four years, Flyway has brought over 120 filmmakers and film professionals into the local community. In addition to screening their remarkable films, it has become a unique venue for these filmmakers to network and discuss projects and the &#8220;state of the industry&#8221; in the film world.</p>
<p>Past Flyway guests of honor have included award-winning producer Ted Hope (Super, American Splendor), Brian Newman, SpringBoardMedia and former CEO of the Tribeca Film Festival; director/author Kelley Baker, (Birddog, “The Angry Filmmaker Survival Guide: Making the Extreme No Budget Film”); and director/author Jon Reiss (Bomb It, “Think Outside the Box Office”).</p>
<p>2012’s esteemed Festival speakers will be <strong>Scilla Andreen, Co-founder and CEO of IndieFlix</strong>, and <strong>Paul Rachman, director/founder of the Slamdance Film Festival</strong>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/2012-official-selections/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Dog With Pleas- #SaveFlyway</title>
		<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/a-dog-with-pleas-saveflyway/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 16:34:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flywayfilmfestival.org/?p=22991</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Paddington may be the unofficial mascot of the 2012 Flyway Film Festival, and you should listen carefully. &#160;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Paddington may be the unofficial mascot of the 2012 Flyway Film Festival, and you should listen carefully.</p>
<p><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/a-dog-with-pleas-saveflyway/"><em>Click here to view the embedded video.</em></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>And Now An Unpaid Celebrity Endorsement By Reed Farrington</title>
		<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/and-now-an-unpaid-celebrity-endorsement-by-reed-farrington/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 03:33:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flywayfilmfestival.org/?p=22451</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Tonight, star power is shining just a little bit brighter (and more damply) on the 2012 Flyway Film Festival&#8217;s Kickstarter campaign with celebrity Reed Farrington (aka, Gerry Eng), of Cooking With Gerry (a 2011 Flyway audience favorite) and a Very Gerry Xmas fame, plunging into the fray with his eloquent words of encouragement. This announcement is [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>Tonight, star power is shining just a little bit brighter (and more damply) on the 2012 Flyway Film Festival&#8217;s Kickstarter campaign with celebrity Reed Farrington (aka, Gerry Eng), of <em>Cooking With Gerry</em> (a 2011 Flyway audience favorite) and a<em> Very Gerry Xmas</em> fame, plunging into the fray with his eloquent words of encouragement.</div>
<div></div>
<div>This announcement is brought to you by Flyway Award-winning director Jay Cheel, Beauty Day (2011 Best Documentary) and Colore Non Vedenti.</div>
<div></div>
<div>We are very grateful for all the buzz and support building toward our $10K!</div>
<div></div>
<div><p><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/and-now-an-unpaid-celebrity-endorsement-by-reed-farrington/"><em>Click here to view the embedded video.</em></a></p></div>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Indie Film Heavyweights Step Up in Support of Flyway&#8217;s Kickstarter Campaign</title>
		<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/indie-film-heavyweights-step-up-in-support-of-flyways-kickstarter-campaign-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 14:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flywayfilmfestival.org/?p=22308</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; Pepin, WI—The 5th Annual 2012 Flyway Film Festival (October 18-21, 2012) announces the launch of a Kickstarter fundraising campaign SAVE FLYWAY to assist with operational costs of the 2012 Festival in Pepin and Stockholm, Wisconsin via an 18-day campaign with the goal of raising $10K. Early response to this effort from past Flyway alumni [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Pepin, WI—The 5<sup>th</sup> Annual 2012 Flyway Film Festival (October 18-21, 2012) announces the launch of a Kickstarter fundraising campaign<a title="Save Flyway" href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/2010774505/save-flyway" target="_blank"> <strong>SAVE FLYWAY</strong></a> to assist with operational costs of the 2012 Festival in Pepin and Stockholm, Wisconsin via an 18-day campaign with the goal of raising $10K.</p>
<div id="attachment_22309" style="width: 285px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/08/IMG_8136_21.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-22309 colorbox-22308" title="IMG_8136_2" src="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/08/IMG_8136_21-275x300.jpg" alt="" width="275" height="300" srcset="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/08/IMG_8136_21-275x300.jpg 275w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/08/IMG_8136_21-551x600.jpg 551w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/08/IMG_8136_21.jpg 587w" sizes="(max-width: 275px) 100vw, 275px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Ted Hope browses the 2011 2012 Flyway Film Festival Program Guide</p></div>
<div id="attachment_22310" style="width: 209px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/08/002-copy1.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-22310 colorbox-22308" title="Brian head shot" src="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/08/002-copy1-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" srcset="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/08/002-copy1-199x300.jpg 199w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/08/002-copy1-682x1024.jpg 682w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/08/002-copy1-399x600.jpg 399w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/08/002-copy1-200x300.jpg 200w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/08/002-copy1-800x1200.jpg 800w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/08/002-copy1.jpg 1123w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Brian Newman Founder of Sub-Genre</p></div>
<p>Early response to this effort from past Flyway alumni and respected film industry personnel has been tremendous. Past Flyway guests of note Ted Hope (Academy Award-Nominated Producer of <em>21 Grams </em>and<em> American Splendor</em> and current Executive Director of the San Francisco Film Society) and Brian Newman (Founder/consultant at Sub-genre Media, focusing on entertainment and cultural industry business development and distribution, and former CEO of the Tribeca Film Institute) have each offered a coveted one-hour private consultation for donors contributing at various levels. Many other quality product, service, and Festival related perks are available at additional donation levels ranging from $25-$2,500+.</p>
<p><span id="more-22308"></span></p>
<p>Kickstarter is an “all or nothing” venture; participants can donate any amount greater than $1, and unless the campaign reaches its set goal within the prescribed timeframe, no funds are collected. Having participated in a positive Kickstarter campaign in 2010, Flyway hopes to replicate and grow that success in order to ensure the resources for a high-quality, engaging experience for its 2012 attending filmmakers and patrons.</p>
<p>As a wholly volunteer-run organization, Flyway relies on the generosity of its sponsors and the dedication of staff who work tirelessly to create a unique film experience for attendees. For 2012, the Festival is again the recipient of a JEM (Joint Effort Marketing) Grant from the Wisconsin Department of Tourism, which will allow continued expansion of marketing to a broader audience.</p>
<p>A good portion of Flyway’s yearly budget is dedicated to deliberate efforts to bring filmmakers, actors, and other film industry personnel from around the world into the regional community—to date, nearly 120 in total. In addition to screening their remarkable films to an accessible, appreciative audience of locals and visitors, Flyway has become a unique venue for these filmmakers to network and discuss projects and the “state of the industry” in the film world.</p>
<p>With a projected 2012 Festival attendance that will contribute over $115K in economic stimulus to its greater community, Flyway’s primary goal remains to continue building its reputation as a festival that matters in an intimate, accessible, and unpretentious way that fosters participation and personal ownership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Reasons Why YOU Should Go to 2012 Flyway Film Festival This Year</title>
		<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/5-reasons-why-you-should-go-to-flyway-film-festival-this-year/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 15:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Post]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flywayfilmfestival.org/?p=21282</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[By Julie Keck &#38; Jessica King of King is a Fink Productions    #1 &#8211; You are a filmmaker. Which means you’re also a fan of film. You made a movie. You want people to see it. And you’d like it to screen somewhere where your hard work is appreciated, talked about, and celebrated: you [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Julie Keck &amp; Jessica King of <a title="@kingisafink" href="http://twitter.com/kingisafink" target="_blank">King is a Fink Productions</a></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong> #1 &#8211; You are a filmmaker. Which means you’re also a fan of film.</strong></p>
<p>You made a movie. You want people to see it. And you’d like it to screen somewhere where your hard work is appreciated, talked about, and celebrated: you want it to screen at 2012 Flyway Film Festival.</p>
<p>Want to know the secret to getting your movie into Flyway? Make a good movie. We’ve had movies that got into Flyway and movies that didn’t, and we 100% respect this. Film festival selections are always subject to the tastes of the programmers, but at Flyway you know that no one got in because they have a big name or a pushy agent. You earn your way in, and this isn’t just good for the filmmakers: it’s good for the audience.</p>
<p>Flyway is not a cattle call like some other overstuffed film festivals. They care about their official selections and the people who make them. They also do everything they can to get the filmmakers there, often offsetting filmmaker travel costs by arranging for transportation (as much as possible) and providing places to stay (through the generosity of the Greater Pepin Area locals, whom we’ll discuss more in a moment.) Last year there were filmmakers present at their Flyway screenings more often then not; what other film festival does that?</p>
<div id="attachment_21285" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/07/1HunterSheri1.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-21285 colorbox-21282" title="1HunterSheri" src="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/07/1HunterSheri1-300x187.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="187" srcset="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/07/1HunterSheri1-300x187.jpg 300w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/07/1HunterSheri1.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Indie Film consultant Sheri Candler and Documentarian Hunter Weeks</p></div>
<p><em></em> <strong>#2 &#8211; You like being around creative people.</strong></p>
<p>At Flyway, everyone hangs out with everyone. The filmmakers, the fans, the people from the community, the festival volunteers, the people who are working on films for next year, the keynote speakers, esteemed panelists&#8230;everyone. So go to Flyway, because that person you’ve been hoping to connect with might be there. Go, because this might be your chance to buy them breakfast and pick their brain. And if that person you wanted to meet doesn’t show up, open your eyes and look around: you just might meet someone you didn’t know before who can open up a whole new world to you. Make a real world connection that leads to an out-of-this-world project.</p>
<div id="attachment_21286" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/07/2GarySusieJulie.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-21286 colorbox-21282" title="2GarySusieJulie" src="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/07/2GarySusieJulie-300x188.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="188" srcset="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/07/2GarySusieJulie-300x188.jpg 300w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/07/2GarySusieJulie.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Filmmakers Gary &amp; Susie King and Julie Keck</p></div>
<p><em></em><strong>#3 &#8211; You want to preserve unique film festival experiences.</strong></p>
<p>Small festivals have it tough, especially when they’re in out-of-the-way places like Pepin. It’s not like going to a festival in LA, where you can roll your screening into other meetings, or New York, where you can shoehorn in some sight seeing. Part of the fun of Flyway is that there’s nowhere else to go. It’s like camp, but without mosquitoes or hot camp counselors or cheesy arts and crafts. The bonding that occurs at the festival is much like camp, too: you become fast friends with the people you eat breakfast with, watch movies with, and talk movies with all weekend long. You don’t just leave with a pocketful of business cards; you leave having established real relationships. It’s an experience like none we’ve had at other film festivals, and, even better, it’s in the center of a community that wants us there.</p>
<div id="attachment_21287" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/07/JamesRamsayPhotography.com-33.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-21287 colorbox-21282" title="JamesRamsayPhotography.com-33" src="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/07/JamesRamsayPhotography.com-33-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/07/JamesRamsayPhotography.com-33-300x200.jpg 300w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/07/JamesRamsayPhotography.com-33-1024x682.jpg 1024w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/07/JamesRamsayPhotography.com-33-600x400.jpg 600w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/07/JamesRamsayPhotography.com-33-800x533.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Kickoff Gala Audience</p></div>
<p><em></em><strong>#4 &#8211; You want someone to see your movie besides your friends and other filmmakers.</strong></p>
<p>At Flyway, you get real eyes on your pride and joy. The aforementioned Pepin/Stockholm/Maiden Rock/Red Wing locals fill the houses at Flyway screenings, many of them artists and artisans themselves. One local artist makes the amazing (and amazingly heavy) Flyway award trophies; another makes the hefty mugs that filmmakers get in their swag bags and others purchase every year as mementos. These people band together not just as a town but as a group of friends supporting Flyway because they know it enriches the place where they live. A community standing up and fighting for its cultural life &#8211; doesn’t get much better than that.</p>
<div id="attachment_21288" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/07/4RickandTheGang.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-21288 colorbox-21282" title="4RickandTheGang" src="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/07/4RickandTheGang-300x188.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="188" srcset="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/07/4RickandTheGang-300x188.jpg 300w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/07/4RickandTheGang.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A beautiful day!</p></div>
<p><strong> #5 &#8211; You’re ready to invest in an adventure.</strong></p>
<p>People think nothing of spending major moolah to go to the big fests (Toronto, Sundance, SXSW, Tribeca) and hobnob with stars. Except&#8230;this never really happens, does it? Make a radical move this year: spend your money on a trip to Pepin for 2012 Flyway Film Festival. Wing it to Chicago, and take a fun train ride the rest of the way. Fly straight to Minneapolis, and split the cost of a car rental with some other out-of-state-ers. Make YOUR Flyway trip a true adventure. And bring friends. The more, the merrier.</p>
<p>If you’ve been to Flyway before, you already know how great it is &#8211; come back. If you’ve never been to Flyway, this is the year to fix that. We’ll see you there.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A love letter to Flyway</title>
		<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/a-love-letter-to-flyway/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2012 15:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flywayfilmfestival.org/?p=19347</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; Let me say this first: this is a love letter about a festival that’s rejected me twice. No, not Sundance, South By, or the other big tables at the festival casino – we’re talking the mother of all indies, the mecca of the git-er-done’s, 2012 Flyway Film Festival, in mighty Pepin, Wisconsin. What? You [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Let me say this first: this is a love letter about a festival that’s rejected me twice.</p>
<div id="attachment_19350" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/KickoffColemanimage.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-19350   colorbox-19347" title="KickoffColemanimage" src="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/KickoffColemanimage-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/KickoffColemanimage-300x199.jpg 300w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/KickoffColemanimage-600x399.jpg 600w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/KickoffColemanimage.jpg 773w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">2011 Kickoff Gala- Film as art installation by Coleman Miller</p></div>
<p>No, not Sundance, South By, or the other big tables at the festival casino – we’re talking the mother of all indies, the mecca of the git-er-done’s, 2012 Flyway Film Festival, in mighty Pepin, Wisconsin. What? You haven’t heard of it? Well that’s fine. Move along. I want to keep it to myself.</p>
<p>I first learned about Flyway from a <a href="http://a.blip.tv/ayearwithoutrent/conversations-with-lucas-rick-vaicius-4943750">video</a> Lucas McNelly posted of Rick Vaicius talking about his festival and the no-application fee. Seemed cute. Aw. No fees! They just want films. Should be easy to get in.</p>
<p>WRONG.</p>
<p><span id="more-19347"></span></p>
<p>I soon learned a lot more people than Lucas had Flyway on their radar as a “must attend.” These are filmmakers I look up to. Filmmakers whose movies I own. Filmmakers with distribution deals. Filmmakers with clout – not the kind with the k.</p>
<div id="attachment_19353" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/IMG_0899_21.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-19353 colorbox-19347" title="IMG_0899_2" src="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/IMG_0899_21-300x224.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="224" srcset="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/IMG_0899_21-300x224.jpg 300w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/IMG_0899_21-600x448.jpg 600w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/IMG_0899_21.jpg 639w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Ted Hope introduces COLLABORATOR Directed by Martin Donovan</p></div>
<p>As I watched my first Flyway come and go on Twitter, the Who’s Who of indie film declared their love for Flyway: King is a Fink. Gary King. Jon Reiss. TED HOPE. So why are these filmmakers – and this is the clincher for me – <em>flying in for an out of the way festival in Wisconsin that they don’t even have a film in.</em> Why? One word: pie.</p>
<p>Well, pie and respect. Nothing goes with pie like a side of respect.</p>
<p>Let’s chat about the pie. Sheri Candler and I were waxing poetic about the pies of Pepin one night, as festival director Rick Vaicius taunted us with rumors of local pastries that make you see stars. (One evening, the conversation grew so painful I made my friend drive me to a pie shop. I am not kidding. I couldn’t drive because I had been drinking margaritas heavily, drowning my Flyway-less woes.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>But the <em>real</em> reason I want to go to Flyway (and am moderately obsessed with it) is that it is a festival  that well-known filmmakers respect. And I believe this is mutual admiration, borne out of the festival’s respect for the medium. It’s the care in choosing films from around the world that make the most of everyone’s time. It’s knowing that your film won’t get in based on some light banter – it has to be earned. And it’s one of the few – if not the only – festival that just might be a meritocracy.</p>
<div id="attachment_19354" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/JamesRamsayPhotography.com-49.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-19354 colorbox-19347" title="JamesRamsayPhotography.com-49" src="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/JamesRamsayPhotography.com-49-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/JamesRamsayPhotography.com-49-300x200.jpg 300w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/JamesRamsayPhotography.com-49-1024x682.jpg 1024w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/JamesRamsayPhotography.com-49-600x400.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Jon Reiss delivers the 2011 Flyway Keynote speech</p></div>
<div id="attachment_19357" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/JamesRamsayPhotography.com-28.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-19357 colorbox-19347" title="JamesRamsayPhotography.com-28" src="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/JamesRamsayPhotography.com-28-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/JamesRamsayPhotography.com-28-300x200.jpg 300w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/JamesRamsayPhotography.com-28-1024x682.jpg 1024w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/JamesRamsayPhotography.com-28-600x400.jpg 600w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/JamesRamsayPhotography.com-28-800x533.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Filmmakers and audience members take in the 2011 Keynote speech</p></div>
<p>Bottom line, Flyway feels like the kind of idealized fest that a young Robert Redford dreamed of: attracting high quality films and people, creating an opportunity for learning and sharing, and rarely even bringing up the question of money. Nobody buys their way into Flyway.</p>
<p>I get a sense of community that I rarely see at other festivals. Filmmakers volunteering. People sharing, spending time with each other, really talking about their passions and their struggles. Friendships form. It’s more of a retreat than a festival. I wish more festivals would adopt the model themselves.</p>
<div id="attachment_19360" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/JulieKeckGaryKingFlywaySpirit.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-19360 colorbox-19347" title="JulieKeckGaryKingFlywaySpirit" src="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/JulieKeckGaryKingFlywaySpirit-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/JulieKeckGaryKingFlywaySpirit-300x200.jpg 300w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/JulieKeckGaryKingFlywaySpirit-600x400.jpg 600w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/JulieKeckGaryKingFlywaySpirit.jpg 710w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Julie Keck (@kingisafink) wins the 2011 Spirit of Flyway Award (Gary King- left)</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I’ll get there, eventually. I don’t even care if I have a film or not in the fest, I just want to go and soak up the conversation, the war stories, the camaraderie. I want to be educated and inspired. And, I want pie. I can get all of that at Flyway.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>By Wonder Russell (@BellaWonder)</p>
<p><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/IMG_1268-3.jpg"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-19348 colorbox-19347" title="IMG_1268 (3)" src="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/IMG_1268-3-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="180" height="180" srcset="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/IMG_1268-3-300x300.jpg 300w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/IMG_1268-3-150x150.jpg 150w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/IMG_1268-3-125x125.jpg 125w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2012/04/IMG_1268-3.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 180px) 100vw, 180px" /></a>Wonder is an actor and filmmaker in Seattle, WA.</p>
<p>Current projects include <a href="http://summerhomefilm.com/">http://summerhomefilm.com</a>, in festivals now.</p>
<p>Revelation Film Project is her directorial debut, coming online Summer of 2012 <a href="http://facebook.com/revelationfilm">http://facebook.com/revelationfilm</a>.</p>
<p>She is an occasional contributor to Film Courage and blogs at <a href="http://bellawonder.com/">bellawonder.com</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Favorite short film ever.</title>
		<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/my-favorite-short-film-ever/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2012 19:54:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flywayfilmfestival.org/?p=16964</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Much mythology surrounds Claude Lelouch&#8217;s 8:40 masterpiece. Who was the driver? Perhaps Lelouch himself. Who was the woman? Lelouch&#8217;s then girlfriend. One take, one shot? Yes. As a film geek, who is also a sportscar geek, this is by far my favorite short film ever. Enjoy! &#160;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Much mythology surrounds Claude Lelouch&#8217;s 8:40 masterpiece.</p>
<p>Who was the driver? Perhaps Lelouch himself.</p>
<p>Who was the woman? Lelouch&#8217;s then girlfriend.</p>
<p>One take, one shot? Yes.</p>
<p>As a film geek, who is also a sportscar geek, this is by far my favorite short film ever.</p>
<p>Enjoy!</p>
<p><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/my-favorite-short-film-ever/"><em>Click here to view the embedded video.</em></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>BAG IT! Saturday January 14th, 7pm at The Widespot in Stockholm</title>
		<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/bag-it-saturday-january-14th-7pm-at-the-widespot-in-stockholm/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 20:19:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flywayfilmfestival.org/?p=16852</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Is your life too plastic? &#160; Our first screening of 2012 is the timely and thought provoking documentary Bag It! Sponsored by Sense or Place, The Widespot Performing Arts Center and The 2012 Flyway Film Festival. Saturday January14th, 7pm Admission is $5.00 at the door Wine and beer available for purchase (with valid ID) &#160;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Is your life too plastic?</p>
<p><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2012/bag-it-saturday-january-14th-7pm-at-the-widespot-in-stockholm/"><em>Click here to view the embedded video.</em></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Our first screening of 2012 is the timely and thought provoking documentary Bag It!</p>
<p>Sponsored by Sense or Place, The Widespot Performing Arts Center and The 2012 Flyway Film Festival.</p>
<p>Saturday January14th, 7pm</p>
<p>Admission is $5.00 at the door</p>
<p>Wine and beer available for purchase (with valid ID)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
