<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Guest Post &#8211; 2011 FFF</title>
	<atom:link href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/category/guest-post/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011</link>
	<description>The Best Indie Fest on Lake Pepin</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 00:02:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.8.6</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Guest Post: Day 0 of Brian Kazmarck&#8217;s TERMINAL LEGACY</title>
		<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-day-0-of-brian-kazmarcks-terminal-legacy/</link>
		<comments>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-day-0-of-brian-kazmarcks-terminal-legacy/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 07:35:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Post]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/06/guest-post-day-0-of-brian-kazmarcks-terminal-legacy/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[by Lucas McNelly&#160; My phone says I&#8217;m supposed to meet Brian Kazmarck at Penn Station in NYC. Wait, let me back up&#8211;way the fuck up&#8211;all the way back to 1999. I went to a small liberal arts college in Western Pennsylvania called Geneva College. There&#8217;s no film program at Geneva College. None at all. Barely [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_autopost">by <a href="http://www.ayearwithoutrent.com">Lucas McNelly</a>&nbsp;</p>
<div><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="Untitled by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5789509985/"><img class="colorbox-10369"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5305/5789509985_4d543d8c14_z.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="281" /></a></div>
<div>My phone says I&#8217;m supposed to meet Brian Kazmarck at Penn Station in NYC.</p>
<p>Wait, let me back up&#8211;way the fuck up&#8211;all the way back to 1999. I went to a small liberal arts college in Western Pennsylvania called Geneva College. There&#8217;s no film program at Geneva College. None at all. Barely any video facilities. The school&#8217;s major claim to fame is that it hosted the very first college basketball game. I spent a good chunk of my time there serving as the radio play-by-play guy, which involved a lot of travel and a lot of basketball. I enjoyed the hell out of it.</p>
<p><span id="more-10369"></span></p>
<p>The first time in my life I picked up a video camera was my final semester when I decided that, what the hell, I&#8217;d enter the school&#8217;s film festival. I won. And no, you can&#8217;t watch it.</p>
<p>Anyway, for one year (or maybe two) Brian Kazmarck lived on my floor. He didn&#8217;t want to be a filmmaker either. Then, he transferred and I didn&#8217;t hear anything about him until Facebook took off. I talked him into going to DIY Days last year and whenever I&#8217;m in NYC, we try and connect.</p>
<p>And now, I&#8217;m looking for him in the middle of Penn Station so we can get in a car and drive to the set of his debut feature TERMINAL LEGACY, in Delaware. Yes, Delaware. That mecca of indie film.</p>
<p>I know they&#8217;ve already been shooting, so my Day 1 is really Day 10, with a bunch of locations around the city, including a morgue where the script supervisor may or may not have found a dead body.</p>
<p>Seriously, I can&#8217;t be on set for <em>that</em>? Bad luck, I guess.</p>
<p>I find Brian easily enough. One by one the other people show up and 5 of us squeeze into a 2 door that thankfully has a big trunk.</p>
<p>Best I can tell, TERMINAL LEGACY is about a scientist (Cuyle Carvin) and some sort of airborne virus that&#8217;s killing people or making them crazy or something. It&#8217;s kind of hard to hear in the back seat.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re filming in the house of co-writer/actor/producer Kazy Tauginas&#8217;s parents in Newark, Delaware. It&#8217;s not a big house, but it&#8217;s big enough. There&#8217;s an upstair area that should work pretty well as a staging area for actors and whatnot, a garage to store gear, and a basement to store even more stuff.</p>
<p>Kazy&#8217;s parents, they&#8217;ll be serving as our craft services.</p>
<p>But for tonight, it&#8217;s just the 5 of us. They rest of the cast and crew are due to arrive tomorrow in a 15 passenger van. It&#8217;s nice to have a couple of hours to relax before the madness starts. And hey, there&#8217;s a bar down the street, which is something.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="Untitled by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5831386783/"><img class="colorbox-10369"  src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3007/5831386783_273eb6e2e7_z.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>*******</p>
<p>Sure enough, the rest of the cast and crew show up the next day around noon. There&#8217;s a lot of them in a pretty small house. It&#8217;s the first sense of just how packed this might be.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="Untitled by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5831394367/"><img class="colorbox-10369"  src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3662/5831394367_116eca53ec_z.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>There&#8217;s not much to the day. Some blocking, some unpacking, some organization of the house. I spend a couple of hours editing UP COUNTRY on the couch.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a lot of the art department making the house look right for the film, part of which involves me taking a bunch of candids of Cuyle and Whitney Kirk outside the house. Basic photos to put over the mantle, stuff like that.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="Untitled by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5831939230/"><img class="colorbox-10369"  src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3264/5831939230_04da9e1b5d_z.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>Kazy&#8217;s parents rent out a townhouse closer to the University of Delaware that&#8217;s (mostly) empty. The guys are staying there. It&#8217;s near a convenience store. At least that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re told. In reality, you have to walk through the woods, then a graveyard and a construction site to get to the convenience store. It&#8217;s a little weird, a little creepy. And that&#8217;s before I found the face drawn on one of the graves.</p>
<p>And they say Delaware is boring.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="Untitled by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5831391239/"><img class="colorbox-10369"  src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3519/5831391239_306338bd1e_z.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p><em>Filmmaker <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm2941069/">Lucas McNelly</a> is spending a year on the road, volunteering on indie film projects around the country, documenting the process and the exploring the idea of a mobile creative professional. You can see more from <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.ayearwithoutrent.com/">A Year Without Rent</a> at the webpage. His feature-length debut is now available to <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.blancdeblancfilm.com/">rent on VOD</a>. Follow him on Twitter: <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.twitter.com/lmcnelly">@lmcnelly</a>.</em></p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-day-0-of-brian-kazmarcks-terminal-legacy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guest Post: Day 2 of Kris and Lindy Boustedt&#8217;s THE SUMMER HOME</title>
		<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-day-2-of-kris-and-lindy-boustedts-the-summer-home/</link>
		<comments>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-day-2-of-kris-and-lindy-boustedts-the-summer-home/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 17:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Post]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>
		<description><![CDATA[by Lucas McNelly It&#8217;s a sunrise call for the first shooting day of THE SUMMER HOME. The first scene, as we saw yesterday, involves a shoot at first light on a dock. Almost immediately it starts raining. Welcome to Seattle. The dock we&#8217;re on is maybe 5 feet wide. There are no posts securing it [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_autopost">by <a href="http://www.ayearwithoutrent.com">Lucas McNelly</a></p>
<div><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="Untitled by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5722624341/"><img class="colorbox-10030"  src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3394/5722624341_141560711a_z.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="281" /></a></div>
<div>It&#8217;s a sunrise call for the first shooting day of THE SUMMER HOME. The first scene, as we saw yesterday, involves a shoot at first light on a dock.</p>
<p>Almost immediately it starts raining. Welcome to Seattle.</p>
<p><span id="more-10030"></span></p>
<p>The dock we&#8217;re on is maybe 5 feet wide. There are no posts securing it in the corners&#8211;just a big post at the end&#8211;and the entire thing pivots on a line from the shore to the post like a big see-saw. So picture that dock and how, um, unstable that could be. Now, put a RED camera on it, along with six people, actor Paul Vitulli on a chair, sound equipment, and a monitor. In a misting rain.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="Untitled by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5722652913/"><img class="colorbox-10030"  src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3559/5722652913_8b752217f5_z.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>Well, make that five people, as it took Eric the sound guy exactly 30 seconds to decide he&#8217;d be much better off just standing in the ankle-deep water. I&#8217;m not sure I blame him.</p>
<p>Luckily, it&#8217;s not a complicated scene, so we&#8217;re in and out (out and in?) pretty quickly. And most of that stuff discussed in the video? That whole discussion about match cuts? Tossed.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="Untitled by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5731712264/"><img class="colorbox-10030"  src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3593/5731712264_cf026d55c0_z.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>But isn&#8217;t that essentially what figuring out a scene is all about? You come up with the scene when you write it, and in your head it looks perfect, but your DP sees it differently in his head. Your actor too. And in order to get everyone on the same page, you go through the scene, beat by beat, trying to figure out the best, most efficient way to do it. Very often you&#8217;ll have 3 or 4 versions of that. Sometimes (rarely) you get it right the first time. But the important thing is the process, because it&#8217;s there that you really dig into the scene. The deeper you can dig, the richer the final product will be, even something as simple as a guy sitting on a dock at sunrise.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re working a film like THE SUMMER HOME, where there&#8217;s fewer than 5 lines of dialogue, then it becomes even more important. There&#8217;s no exposition scene where Character A tells Character B something Really Important, so you really have to know not just what narrative points you&#8217;re trying to get across with a scene, but whether or not they&#8217;ll be noticed by the audience. Easier said than done.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="Untitled by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5722645665/"><img class="colorbox-10030"  src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2107/5722645665_833916cf43_z.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>For the rest of the day we&#8217;re pretty much in the bedroom. The location has a garage, which we&#8217;ve cleaned out to function as a staging area, so while the house is small, we&#8217;re able to at least move around more or less freely.</p>
<p>Plus, we&#8217;ve got a fiery Executive Producer who demands attention at every opportunity. Seriously, Falcor has more energy than the rest of the cast and crew combined.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="Executive Producer by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5723172142/"><img class="colorbox-10030"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5230/5723172142_a61d3c16cd.jpg" alt="Executive Producer" width="500" height="311" /></a></p>
<p>It&#8217;s a long day, wrapping late in the night and the turnaround is short, which is far from ideal, but it&#8217;s the film everyone signed up for. And Wonder Russell brought lots of beer.</p>
<p>You can ask a crew to do a lot if you supply beer.</p>
<p><em>Filmmaker <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm2941069/">Lucas McNelly</a> is spending a year on the road, volunteering on indie film projects around the country, documenting the process and the exploring the idea of a mobile creative professional. You can see more from <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.ayearwithoutrent.com/">A Year Without Rent</a> at the webpage. His feature-length debut is now available to <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.blancdeblancfilm.com/">rent on VOD</a>. Follow him on Twitter: <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.twitter.com/lmcnelly">@lmcnelly</a>.</em></p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-day-2-of-kris-and-lindy-boustedts-the-summer-home/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guest Post: Dawn Mikkelson&#8217;s SMOOCH</title>
		<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-dawn-mikkelsons-smooch/</link>
		<comments>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-dawn-mikkelsons-smooch/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 22:06:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Post]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/05/guest-post-dawn-mikkelsons-smooch/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[by Lucas McNelly&#160; I&#8217;m standing on Rick Vaicius&#8217; lawn in Pepin, Wisconsin, eating a brat and drinking beer when he asks what the next project is. &#8220;Oh, it&#8217;s this documentary in Minneapolis about kissing.&#8221; &#8220;You mean SMOOCH?&#8221; &#8220;Yeah.&#8221; &#8220;That&#8217;s not about kissing.&#8221; Such is the tenuous grasp I sometimes have on what these films I&#8217;m [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_autopost">by Lucas McNelly&nbsp;</p>
<div><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="boom by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5691915100/"><img class="colorbox-7933"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5106/5691915100_139ca13e29_z.jpg" alt="boom" width="500" height="281" /></a></div>
<div>I&#8217;m standing on Rick Vaicius&#8217; lawn in Pepin, Wisconsin, eating a brat and drinking beer when he asks what the next project is.</p>
<p>&#8220;Oh, it&#8217;s this documentary in Minneapolis about kissing.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;You mean SMOOCH?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Yeah.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;That&#8217;s not about kissing.&#8221;</p>
<p><span id="more-7933"></span></p>
<p>Such is the tenuous grasp I sometimes have on what these films I&#8217;m working on are about. I get the gist of it and I usually remember part of it. Anyway, what&#8217;s important is that I show up at the right place at the right time. Beyond that, I don&#8217;t really need to know what&#8217;s going on. It doesn&#8217;t affect what I&#8217;m going to do anyway.</p>
<p>Anyway, Rick was right. SMOOCH is not about kissing. And I was right, it sort of is.</p>
<p>You see, there&#8217;s <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.thesmoochprojectgalleries.com/">The Smooch Project</a>, a &#8220;heart-lifting effort to collect 10,000 photographs of the affectionately-inclined from around the world.&#8221; Go to the webpage. There&#8217;s lots of cute pictures.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="full room by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5691345339/"><img class="colorbox-7933"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5107/5691345339_325ecb5a9c_z.jpg" alt="full room" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>An off-shoot of that is Dawn Mikkelson&#8217;s documentary <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.smoochdocumentary.com/">SMOOCH</a>, a film that aims to show &#8220;stories of reconciliation, forgiveness and healing from some of the most conflict-ridden nations in the world.&#8221;</p>
<div class="post-body entry-content" style="line-height: 1.4;"><p><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-dawn-mikkelsons-smooch/"><em>Click here to view the embedded video.</em></a></p></div>
<p>I&#8217;m in town for the documentary part.</p>
<p>The team for the day (other than myself) is pretty small: director (and proud backer) Dawn Mikkelson and interns Monte Swann and Heidi Tungseth, and that&#8217;s probably for the best because we&#8217;re in the storage unit of an apartment complex. Yes, the storage unit.</p>
<p><p><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-dawn-mikkelsons-smooch/"><em>Click here to view the embedded video.</em></a></p>As people come through the building&#8217;s art crawl to get their Smooch pictures taken, we tell them about the documentary and try and convince them to come back into the scary room to talk about forgiveness on-camera. It&#8217;s pretty simple, really. The trick is just convincing normal people to do something like this.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="heidi and dawn by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5691919574/"><img class="colorbox-7933"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5264/5691919574_169bae52cd_z.jpg" alt="heidi and dawn" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>Once we&#8217;ve loaded in, there isn&#8217;t a whole lot to it. The talking head interviews are pretty straightforward. As long as people stay on their marks and don&#8217;t do anything weird, it&#8217;s just a matter of capturing emotions and asking the right questions.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="republicans by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5691922898/"><img class="colorbox-7933"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5182/5691922898_6089267b8d_z.jpg" alt="republicans" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>It was all pretty basic stuff&#8211;fodder for the <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.youtube.com/user/SmoochDocumentary">YouTube channel</a>&#8211;and then a middle aged woman in a wheelchair rolled in and blew us away. You could feel the film exploding all around the room. I don&#8217;t want to get into the details, but it was a powerful, powerful story. You could easily do a whole film on her. And that&#8217;s awesome, but it doesn&#8217;t really fit with the narrative the film has been following.</p>
<p>So what then does a documentary do when the world it has built implodes? I guess we&#8217;ll see.</p>
<p><p><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-dawn-mikkelsons-smooch/"><em>Click here to view the embedded video.</em></a></p><em>Filmmaker <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm2941069/">Lucas McNelly</a> is spending a year on the road, volunteering on indie film projects around the country, documenting the process and the exploring the idea of a mobile creative professional. You can see more from <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.ayearwithoutrent.com/">A Year Without Rent</a> at the webpage. Follow him on Twitter: <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.twitter.com/lmcnelly">@lmcnelly</a>.</em></p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-dawn-mikkelsons-smooch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guest Post: Day 3 of Dave Bullis&#8217; GAME OVER</title>
		<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-day-3-of-dave-bullis-game-over/</link>
		<comments>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-day-3-of-dave-bullis-game-over/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2011 16:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Post]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/05/guest-post-day-3-of-dave-bullis-game-over/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[by Lucas McNelly&#160; Lots of films have bad days. Some of them are just slightly annoying, while others end up being a full-fledged clusterfuck. You can&#8217;t get rid of them entirely, you just have to hope it isn&#8217;t too bad and doesn&#8217;t have a domino effect on the whole project, as one really terrible day [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_autopost">by Lucas McNelly&nbsp;</p>
<div><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="aspiring dj by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5611244689/"><img class="colorbox-7813"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5024/5611244689_2918157d38_z.jpg" alt="aspiring dj" width="500" height="281" /></a></div>
<div>Lots of films have bad days. Some of them are just slightly annoying, while others end up being a full-fledged clusterfuck. You can&#8217;t get rid of them entirely, you just have to hope it isn&#8217;t too bad and doesn&#8217;t have a domino effect on the whole project, as one really terrible day can kill a film.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span id="more-7813"></span></p>
<p>Assuming you survive, one of the big tests is how the production responds. Does it rally, making up the difference and then some? Or does it kind of sputter along, not making things worse, but not really fixing anything either?</p>
<p>You may recall that Day 2 on GAME OVER was a <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.ayearwithoutrent.com/2011/04/day-2-of-dave-bullis-game-over.html">terrible, horrible, no good, very bad day</a>. Very little went well and, honestly, I thought we were minutes away from a meltdown at a couple of different points. So how did the production respond? Let&#8217;s take a look.</p>
<p><strong>The Night Before</strong></p>
<p>As soon as filming wrapped for the night, there was an impromptu meeting far from earshot between several production heads. I don&#8217;t imagine it was a pleasant conversation.</p>
<p>Which is how myself, director Dave Bullis, 1st AD Zach Zimmerman, 2nd AD Michael O&#8217;Donnell, and the only PA worth a damn (Eric Torbio) ended up in Dave&#8217;s living room, trying to sort thing out over cheesesteaks.</p>
<p>My theory: the production lacks a motor to keep all the different departments moving forward. A number of times in Day 2, things got bogged down (or stopped completely) for no reason whatsoever. That&#8217;s not good.</p>
<p>I offer to be more assertive on-set when things start to slow down.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="swan by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5606152560/"><img class="colorbox-7813"  src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4104/5606152560_b809ee9dc7_z.jpg" alt="swan" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Day 3</strong></p>
<p>One thing discussed at the meeting the night before was the utter worthlessness of several of the film&#8217;s PA&#8217;s (other than Eric). Apparently, they were recruited from a local high school and essentially spent the entire day leaning up against a wall, doing whatever it is kids do these days. This isn&#8217;t entirely their fault, as I&#8217;m pretty sure no one was really in charge of them. That&#8217;s part of it, but I know for a fact they were given things to do and just didn&#8217;t feel like it.</p>
<p>So, since they weren&#8217;t doing anything, every time I walked by a PA leaning up against a wall, I gave them something to do. Some of it was important. Some of it wasn&#8217;t. I had one PA tape a trail from the set to the Green Room, since people were constantly getting lost. They spent a lot of time running messages back to the Green Room for us, stuff like how long until we&#8217;d need an actor. They were mostly ok with it, except for this exchange:</p>
<p>Me: &#8220;You a PA?&#8221;<br />
PA: &#8220;Yeah&#8221;<br />
Me: &#8220;I need you to get [coffee order] for the DP and AC.&#8221;<br />
He started to chuckle.<br />
Me: &#8220;It&#8217;s not fucking funny. Go. Now.&#8221;</p>
<p>He got the message (but screwed up the coffee order). More importantly, it scared him into be slightly helpful, instead of just one more mouth to feed. And when I told Dave that I had started yelling at his PAs, he smiled.</p>
<p>&#8220;Awesome.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sometimes you&#8217;ve just got to have a bad guy, and who better than the person who&#8217;s leaving town as soon as the production is over?</p>
<p>Motivation is high, as everyone knows that the production is under the gun, time-wise. Things move at a decent clip, not frenetic, not slow. New on set for day 3 is photographer and cinematographer Marvin Burwell, who loans me a wide-angle lens to play with.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="dj1 by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5611246031/"><img class="colorbox-7813"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5226/5611246031_ee02413995_z.jpg" alt="dj1" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>And so, not really knowing how to shoot effectively with a wide-angle lens (this is why I get a cinematographer), I wander around until actress <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.facebook.com/tammyjeanthebeautyqueen">Tammy Jean</a> (who&#8217;s playing the DJ in the party for the new video game system) gives me a few pointers. Then, Marvin checks in to give me a few more.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t think a whole lot of it until a couple of days later when I do my standard basic research of everyone I might potentially write about (I find some interesting tidbits that way), and discover that Tammy was (is?) a Playboy model, something no one bothered to tell me. I&#8217;ll let you do the NSFW Googling at your discretion.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="tammy jean2 by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5611246307/"><img class="colorbox-7813"  src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4100/5611246307_441af93770_z.jpg" alt="tammy jean2" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>The day moves along. The time for lunch comes and goes. We keep filming. Finally, we break for lunch. Only, there is no lunch. The crew wanders around the holding area, snacking on carrots and whatnot. 15 minutes. Still no lunch. The producers don&#8217;t know where it is. Neither does the director. No one does. I lay down on a wrestling mat they were using for some stunt practice. 30 minutes passes. It&#8217;s 40 minutes before the decision is made to start setting up for the first post-lunch shot. 5 minutes later the food shows up. All that momentum gained during the day is lost. A ravenous crew eats and rushes back to work. By this point, the day is almost over. We won&#8217;t get our pages. Obviously, another day of filming is going to be needed, but when?</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="officer down by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5611831054/"><img class="colorbox-7813"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5184/5611831054_f044856a1b_z.jpg" alt="officer down" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>Actor Kenneth McGregor has to leave in 20 minutes, but his big stunt move is still left. He starts taking over, making sure they get it before he has to leave, directing the other actors. Clearly he&#8217;s done this before. We get the stunt. Kenneth runs to the car. We shoot a few more setups and then we have to be out. In no way are they done.</p>
<p>Will it cut together? Honestly, I don&#8217;t know. They&#8217;ll need at least another day of filming, maybe more. As for me, I&#8217;ve got to be on the road. So while that&#8217;s not a wrap for GAME OVER, it is for me.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="wade is beat by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5611829556/"><img class="colorbox-7813"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5229/5611829556_0bb6d45ecb_z.jpg" alt="wade is beat" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p><em>Filmmaker <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm2941069/">Lucas McNelly</a> is spending a year on the road, volunteering on indie film projects around the country, documenting the process and the exploring the idea of a mobile creative professional. You can see more from <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.ayearwithoutrent.com/">A Year Without Rent</a> at the webpage. Follow him on Twitter: <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.twitter.com/lmcnelly">@lmcnelly</a>.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
<div class="post-footer" style="line-height: 1.6; margin-top: 1.5em; margin-right: 0px; margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px;">
<div class="post-footer-line post-footer-line-1">
<div class="post-share-buttons goog-inline-block" style="margin-top: 0px !important; margin-right: 0.5em !important; margin-bottom: 0px !important; margin-left: 0.5em !important; vertical-align: middle; display: inline-block;"><a class="goog-inline-block share-button sb-email" title="Email This" href="http://www.blogger.com/share-post.g?blogID=11979056&amp;postID=8208247957828607471&amp;target=email" target="_blank"></a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-day-3-of-dave-bullis-game-over/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guest Post: Camden Printworks</title>
		<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-camden-printworks/</link>
		<comments>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-camden-printworks/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2011 13:27:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Post]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/04/guest-post-camden-printworks/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[by Lucas McNelly&#160; You know the movie where the white kid from the country goes to the big city for the first time, only to see the bright lights have been replaced by urban blight, graffiti, old cars on blocks, and all sorts of frightening stereotypes? That&#8217;s what it&#8217;s like to drive through Camden, NJ, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_autopost">by Lucas McNelly&nbsp;</p>
<div><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="sasquatch by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5611838350/"><img class="colorbox-7068"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5188/5611838350_dde6efac7a_z.jpg" alt="sasquatch" width="500" height="281" /></a></div>
<div>You know the movie where the white kid from the country goes to the big city for the first time, only to see the bright lights have been replaced by urban blight, graffiti, old cars on blocks, and all sorts of frightening stereotypes? That&#8217;s what it&#8217;s like to drive through Camden, NJ, even on a Monday at 10am.</p>
<p><span id="more-7068"></span></p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="monkey by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5611839154/"><img class="colorbox-7068"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5228/5611839154_801fdbc5c3_z.jpg" alt="monkey" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Camden, <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Camden,_New_Jersey">if you aren&#8217;t aware</a>, is pretty much the poorest, most dangerous place in the whole country, and has been for about a decade. It&#8217;s not exactly the type of place a kid from Maine who went to private school spends a lot of time. So what am I doing there? Well, that&#8217;s where our long-time t-shirt company is located. I&#8217;ll let head honcho Adam Woods <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://camdenprintworks.net/social_mission.html">explain why</a>:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote><p><em>The city of Camden, New Jersey is not without its problems. Consistently ranked among America&#8217;s poorest and most dangerous cities, a quick googling of Camden, New Jersey, says it all. We&#8217;re excited about Camden&#8217;s potential for rebirth and we want to be a part of it. So far we&#8217;re trying by paying between double and triple the prevailing local wage, offering discounted health insurance to our staff, emphasizing sales on American-made and fairly-made goods, and staying on the cusp of our industry&#8217;s efforts to &#8220;go green.&#8221;</em>&nbsp;</p></blockquote>
<p>So, they&#8217;re good people.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="orange by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5611839954/"><img class="colorbox-7068"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5062/5611839954_dda1980df3_z.jpg" alt="orange" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.twitter.com/adamewoods">Adam Woods</a>, in particular, has been one of my most ardent supporters. I used to write for a magazine he ran back in the day and Adam designed the t-shirt worn by Kieran Roberts in UP COUNTRY.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="kieran inside camp by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5076023874/"><img class="colorbox-7068"  src="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1064/5076023874_4bf0c41211_z.jpg" alt="kieran inside camp" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>So when I was designing the <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://kck.st/dExFQg">Kickstarter campaign</a>, Adam was one of the first people I contacted. He agreed to make our shirts for super cheap, so being in the area, I stopped in to see how that was going. Plus, we needed to start brainstorming what the A Year Without Rent shirt itself should look like. Sure, we could just put the logo on a shirt and call it good, but what fun would that be?</p>
<div class="post-body entry-content" style="line-height: 1.4;"><p><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-camden-printworks/"><em>Click here to view the embedded video.</em></a></p></div>
<div class="post-body entry-content" style="line-height: 1.4;"></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Filmmaker <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm2941069/">Lucas McNelly</a> is spending a year on the road, volunteering on indie film projects around the country, documenting the process and the exploring the idea of a mobile creative professional. You can see more from <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.ayearwithoutrent.com/">A Year Without Rent</a> at the webpage. Follow him on Twitter: <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.twitter.com/lmcnelly">@lmcnelly</a>.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
<div class="post-footer" style="line-height: 1.6; margin-top: 1.5em; margin-right: 0px; margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px;">
<div class="post-footer-line post-footer-line-1">
<div class="post-share-buttons goog-inline-block" style="margin-top: 0px !important; margin-right: 0.5em !important; margin-bottom: 0px !important; margin-left: 0.5em !important; vertical-align: middle; display: inline-block;"><a class="goog-inline-block share-button sb-email" title="Email This" href="http://www.blogger.com/share-post.g?blogID=11979056&amp;postID=3229292395262845089&amp;target=email" target="_blank"></a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-camden-printworks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guest Post: Get Your Shit Together</title>
		<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-get-your-shit-together/</link>
		<comments>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-get-your-shit-together/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 17:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Post]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/04/guest-post-get-your-shit-together/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[by Lucas McNelly&#160; Right now, I&#8217;m supposed to be in Tampa, Florida, working on a romantic comedy. Well, wait, that&#8217;s not completely true. Tampa was just the Plan B that came together after the family drama in Seattle fell apart. So, I&#8217;m supposed to be in Seattle right now. &#160; I&#8217;m not. I&#8217;m once again [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_autopost">by <a href="http://www.lucasmcnelly.com">Lucas McNelly</a>&nbsp;</p>
<div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, Geneva, sans-serif; font-size: 12px; line-height: 16px;"><img class="colorbox-6848"  src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Cfkm8njax18/TbWdfdFMXOI/AAAAAAAAATc/8unvVOcEO4A/s1600/chaos-reigns-637x2651-583x242.jpg" border="0" alt="" width="500px" /></span></div>
<div>Right now, I&#8217;m supposed to be in Tampa, Florida, working on a romantic comedy. Well, wait, that&#8217;s not completely true. Tampa was just the Plan B that came together after the family drama in Seattle fell apart. So, I&#8217;m supposed to be in Seattle right now.</div>
<div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, Geneva, sans-serif; font-size: 12px; line-height: 16px;">&nbsp;</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not.</p>
<p><span id="more-6848"></span></p>
<p>I&#8217;m once again in Pittsburgh, sleeping on the couches of friends and trying to plug the hole in the schedule. Again.</p>
<p>I know, I know, my frustration is seeping through a little bit. But, we&#8217;re looking at 8 cancellations in the first 8 weeks of this project. Some of them are situations out of people&#8217;s control. And some of them are because the production is apparently being run by chaos. It takes all kinds, I guess.</p>
<p>Our discussions with one filmmaker (who I won&#8217;t name), was so nearly finalized, that I was simply waiting for him to confirm a pickup time so that I could purchase a plane ticket. The issue being what time they could spare a PA to grab me at the airport. That was the last I heard from that production. It&#8217;s probably for the best, because the last thing I need is to be stranded at the airport.</p>
<p>I actually don&#8217;t even know if they wrapped the project or what. Maybe they&#8217;re all being held hostage by the Tea Party, and then won&#8217;t I feel terrible? Eh, probably not.</p>
<p>Or when they aren&#8217;t canceling, filmmakers are contacting us with emails like this:</p>
<p>&#8220;Hey, we&#8217;re shooting this thing that sort of kind of sounds like a short tomorrow and would love to have you come by.&#8221;</p>
<p>Of course, we don&#8217;t really know where that is, or what time tomorrow. Is it 50 miles away? 500?</p>
<p>This strikes me as some pretty terrible planning, but &#8220;A Year Without Rent&#8221; is a pretty odd project, so maybe it&#8217;s just us. And then I started talking to various actor friends of mine. Turns out they get this all the time. They&#8217;ll audition for a role and not hear anything for a long time. Once they finally get cast, they get a vague sense of when filming might be, and then they hear nothing until the day before filming starts, at which point they&#8217;re expected to drop everything.</p>
<p>Seriously, people? You know the boss in OFFICE SPACE who asks you to work during the weekend on Friday afternoon? You&#8217;re that guy. You&#8217;re Bill Lumbergh.</p>
<p>I know it&#8217;s really great to be an artist and be able to sleep in and set your own schedule and be artistic, but if you&#8217;re making a film, you&#8217;re running a small business. Other people are relying on you to function in a somewhat responsible manner. These actors and crew members have lives. They&#8217;re trying to fit your project into their other projects. They have to line up day care, maybe, or go to the doctor or, you know, live their lives.</p>
<p>You owe it to them to, at minimum, operate with some modicum of a business world approach. Set your shooting dates. Stick to them whenever possible. Keep your people in the loop.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m finding that, almost without exception, these films that sort of kind of exist in the air around the director&#8217;s head have no Facebook page. Or, if they do, it has 15 fans. There&#8217;s no Twitter account, not even a director&#8217;s personal account. There&#8217;s no webpage. Nothing at all that would indicate this movie even exists.</p>
<p>Obviously, there&#8217;s no distribution plan beyond &#8220;get picked up by a distributor&#8221;.</p>
<p>Maybe I&#8217;m cramming two different posts together here, but it&#8217;s been pretty clear thus far that the more active the filmmaker is in social media, the more likely the film will happen and be a pleasant experience for everyone. I&#8217;m not really sure why that is. Maybe it&#8217;s because the social media savvy filmmakers have likely raised their money via Kickstarter and therefore don&#8217;t have to worry about an investor falling through? Is it because once you&#8217;ve announced to the filmmaking world that you&#8217;re making a film, there&#8217;s a lot more motivation to get it made? Or is it because you&#8217;d be a damned fool these days to be a filmmaker who isn&#8217;t actively on social media?</p>
<p>I get business cards all the time, and I generally keep them in my pocket long enough to find the person on Facebook or Twitter. And then I throw them away. I have enough crap to carry around.</p>
<p>Someone (I forget who) told me the other day that if a filmmaker isn&#8217;t easy to find on Twitter, they probably won&#8217;t return their call. There&#8217;s exceptions, of course, if the person has a pretty long list of credits on IMDb, but I can see where that comes from. If you can&#8217;t be bothered to find and engage your audience, how well are you going to interact with your cast and crew?</p>
<p>From what I&#8217;m seeing, not very well. Communication is communication, after all. If you suck at it on a keyboard, you probably suck at it in person.</p>
<p>And you can try and cover that up with &#8220;oh but I&#8217;m an artist&#8221; all you want, but a bad boss is a bad boss. It doesn&#8217;t matter if you live in a cubicle or on a film set. Being an artist doesn&#8217;t give you license to make other people deal with your chaos. Or, at least learn to manage it.</p>
<p>Get your shit together. And don&#8217;t even think about going into production until you do. Your film will be better for it.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Filmmaker <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm2941069/">Lucas McNelly</a> is spending a year on the road, volunteering on indie film projects around the country, documenting the process and the exploring the idea of a mobile creative professional. You can see more from <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.ayearwithoutrent.com/">A Year Without Rent</a> at the webpage. Follow him on Twitter: <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.twitter.com/lmcnelly">@lmcnelly</a>.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p></span></div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-get-your-shit-together/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guest Post: Day 2 of Dave Bullis&#8217; GAME OVER</title>
		<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-day-2-of-dave-bullis-game-over/</link>
		<comments>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-day-2-of-dave-bullis-game-over/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 16:19:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Post]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/04/guest-post-day-2-of-dave-bullis-game-over/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[by Lucas McNelly&#160; &#160; Day 2 of GAME OVER starts with the word that we have extras&#8211;lots of little kid extras. And that in the scene we&#8217;re filming, they&#8217;ll be chasing a guy dressed up like a gerbil. Does this invoke the old rule of never working with children or animals? Does it count as [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_autopost">by Lucas McNelly&nbsp;</p>
<div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, Geneva, sans-serif; font-size: 12px; line-height: 16px;"><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="dave by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5605573221/"><img class="colorbox-6378"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5108/5605573221_031fb1459e_z.jpg" alt="dave" width="500" height="281" /></a>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Day 2 of GAME OVER starts with the word that we have extras&#8211;lots of little kid extras. And that in the scene we&#8217;re filming, they&#8217;ll be chasing a guy dressed up like a gerbil. Does this invoke the old rule of never working with children or animals? Does it count as an animal if it&#8217;s just an animal costume? I&#8217;m not sure. On the one hand, the person inside the animal costume can certainly take direction. But…that costume is a hassle. There&#8217;s a lot of moving parts and some of them are held together by safety pins and gaffer tape.</p>
<p><span id="more-6378"></span></p>
<p>The brave soul inside this costume is Vikram Joshi. He&#8217;s got some experience doing stuff like this, but never before as a gerbil. I wonder how much that translates from costume to costume.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="hardcore hindu by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5637493743/"><img class="colorbox-6378"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5310/5637493743_32d26cdd4e_z.jpg" alt="hardcore hindu" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="vicram by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5606154274/"><img class="colorbox-6378"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5188/5606154274_f64471264b_z.jpg" alt="vicram" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>Then there&#8217;s the kids. No one&#8217;s entirely sure just how many of them will descend upon us (in my mind, they show up like locusts in the Bible). And I know that I said I&#8217;d do whatever is needed, but I&#8217;m really hoping that I&#8217;m not on little kid duty. I can handle one little kid, if they&#8217;re related to me. But ten? Twenty? Not so much.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="dark by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5605572451/"><img class="colorbox-6378"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5305/5605572451_21506545ef_z.jpg" alt="dark" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>The scene that involves the kids exists outside of our contained set. The plan is to do a company move over to a local Blockbuster that&#8217;s now shuttered, where we&#8217;ll film a sizable chunk of today&#8217;s footage. But like most plans, that changed on set. Moving that many people that far just didn&#8217;t make a ton of sense when we were in an area that could maybe work as a faked exterior. Eventually, the production settles on a seemingly closed office complex across the street. It makes sense. Vikram&#8217;s gerbil costume isn&#8217;t exactly easy to get in a car, so he can walk. Plus, we&#8217;re closer to our base, which is always helpful.</p>
<p>Of course, we have no permits (and didn&#8217;t for the original location either) but, hey, that&#8217;s indie film for you.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="eric by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5606155528/"><img class="colorbox-6378"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5221/5606155528_b8042dc465_z.jpg" alt="eric" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>The scene is such: Jerry the Gerbil rounds a corner, running pretty much in slow motion (not from a tech standpoint, but a &#8220;this costume makes it impossible to run&#8221; standpoint). He&#8217;s followed by a hoard of screaming children who seem hell-bent on destroying him. They gain quickly and at the last minute, Jerry throws a bunch of tokens on the ground, thus distracting the little monsters so he can make a getaway. We&#8217;ve got 2 cameras running. Easy enough, right? Except, on the first take Vikram trips over his massive feet. He goes tumbling. The rubber tread of the foot rips off. Thankfully, he&#8217;s ok. The rest of it is pretty uneventful. We wrap the children, and we trek back across the street.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="dave brian gerbil by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5606156772/"><img class="colorbox-6378"  src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4105/5606156772_963d37f0e2_z.jpg" alt="dave brian gerbil" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>And then, we come back to film a couple more scenes. It&#8217;s around this time that the production more or less grinds to a halt. Between takes, an actor takes a break in a car and someone (name withheld) drives the car back over to the green room without anyone releasing the actor. That halts things for a good half hour.</p>
<p>On almost every production, there&#8217;s a day when people start to mentally check out for the day. You see this a lot on construction sites when something prevents people from working. Once the work stops, the crew is mentally gone. Sure, you can get them back, but it takes some doing. Today was a day where they didn&#8217;t come back, and I&#8217;m not sure a whole lot of effort was put into attempting to rectify that.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="resting by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5638164398/"><img class="colorbox-6378"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5225/5638164398_81d905fa1d_z.jpg" alt="resting" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>It was, to put it bluntly, a bad day. Tempers flared. Communication broke down. Almost nothing went according to plan.</p>
<p>Having finally finished the outside scenes, we went back to the set, only to discover that props hadn&#8217;t been greeked and the banner announcing the launch party of the &#8220;M2&#8221; game system was actually for the &#8220;M3&#8221;. Apparently no one had bothered to check. Things had spiraled. One problem was that the layout of the location, with a green room far enough away from the set to provide a nice sound buffer, had also served to completely disconnect the two halves. The left hand had no idea what the right hand was doing. So something as simple as telling makeup that an actor was needed in 10 minutes resulted in that actor showing up in 20-25 minutes. Such things add up. Meanwhile, we have PAs standing against a wall, texting their friends.</p>
<p>And, honestly, I&#8217;m not sure what my role is at this point. How much of this do I film? How much of it can I even capture effectively. It&#8217;s not like there&#8217;s a Christian Bale moment. It&#8217;s more of a death by a thousand razors. These things happen to the best of us. There&#8217;s no use pretending they don&#8217;t. Near the end of the day, I was walking down the hallway with one of the crew members and we were talking about how badly the day was going. I somewhat innocently said &#8220;The problem is we don&#8217;t have an AD on this set&#8221;. To which he replied, &#8220;I&#8217;m the AD&#8221;. I looked over at him. &#8220;Then you need to start fucking yelling at people.&#8221;</p>
<p>This is where it would have been really helpful to have a camera crew following me.</p>
<p><em>Filmmaker <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm2941069/">Lucas McNelly</a> is spending a year on the road, volunteering on indie film projects around the country, documenting the process and the exploring the idea of a mobile creative professional. You can see more from <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.ayearwithoutrent.com/">A Year Without Rent</a> at the webpage. Follow him on Twitter: <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.twitter.com/lmcnelly">@lmcnelly</a>.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p></span></div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-day-2-of-dave-bullis-game-over/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guest Post: Day 1 of Dave Bullis&#8217;s GAME OVER</title>
		<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-day-1-of-dave-bulliss-game-over/</link>
		<comments>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-day-1-of-dave-bulliss-game-over/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 14:39:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Post]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/04/guest-post-day-1-of-dave-bulliss-game-over/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[by Lucas McNelly&#160; &#160; There aren&#8217;t a whole lot of moving part to GAME OVER. Much like CLERKS, it exists almost entirely in a small store, the story revolving around the lives of the people who exist in the world of this store and the immediate surroundings. Being a TV show, this makes sense. It [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_autopost">by Lucas McNelly&nbsp;</p>
<div><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Verdana, Geneva, sans-serif; font-size: 12px; line-height: 16px;"><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="operation by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5606150272/"><img class="colorbox-5969"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5308/5606150272_15244bc25e_z.jpg" alt="operation" width="500" height="281" /></a>&nbsp;</p>
<p>There aren&#8217;t a whole lot of moving part to GAME OVER. Much like CLERKS, it exists almost entirely in a small store, the story revolving around the lives of the people who exist in the world of this store and the immediate surroundings. Being a TV show, this makes sense. It makes everything more or less self-contained.</p>
<p>Well, I&#8217;m guessing that&#8217;s the case. I haven&#8217;t read the script.</p>
<p><span id="more-5969"></span></p>
<p><p><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-day-1-of-dave-bulliss-game-over/"><em>Click here to view the embedded video.</em></a></p>It&#8217;s a small set, but it&#8217;s on a parcel of land that&#8217;s pretty well removed from a lot of stuff, which makes it a lot easier to operate. There&#8217;s a large basketball court where we can keep gear and rooms in the back where the unneeded cast and crew can relax without having to worry about talking too loud and ruining the sound. Pretty much we have the run of the place. It&#8217;s a big building that doesn&#8217;t really seem to be doing anything other than this, which is nice.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="basketball by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5602508703/"><img class="colorbox-5969"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5181/5602508703_387c0a68af_z.jpg" alt="basketball" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>Call is 7am and we load in, which takes a bit. The crew is about the size you&#8217;d expect. We start filming around 11am. The first scene revolves around the store&#8217;s chief gamer Trey (Robb Stech) berating a kid who&#8217;s trying to play some video game, and then being too cool to deal with a customer. So, yeah, it&#8217;s a lot like CLERKS. Robb improvises the scene quite a bit, which is effective, as it adds a freshness to the dialogue. Plus, it tends to get better reactions from the other actors.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="don't look at me by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5611826604/"><img class="colorbox-5969"  src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4113/5611826604_dc8008a1d7_z.jpg" alt="don't look at me" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>I&#8217;m not sure why I&#8217;m so surprised that CLERKS is a template for something that takes place in a video store. It&#8217;s a pretty easy series of dots to connect. Maybe I&#8217;m just surprised that we&#8217;re still so thematically beholden to a rather mediocre indie from 15 years ago that wouldn&#8217;t have a shot in hell at finding an audience if it came out today. It just strikes me as a pretty terrible starting point for your story, especially when you consider that CLERKS itself is sort of based on &#8220;The Divine Comedy&#8221;. Why not go back into the original source and work from there? It&#8217;s kind of like basing your love story on TROMEO AND JULIET instead of, you know, Shakespeare. I dunno, it seems like you really limit yourself with that approach.</p>
<p>Just a pet peeve of mine.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="camera by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5605568141/"><img class="colorbox-5969"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5268/5605568141_d5753728fa_z.jpg" alt="camera" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>The real highlight of day 1 is the early stages of <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0532342/">Kenneth McGregor&#8217;s</a> performance as Jim, an older store employee who sort of exists on his own wavelength. Think Kramer, without the caffeine. It&#8217;s always fascinating to watch an experienced actor work, and this is one in full control. He knows his character and, beyond that, he knows the other characters and works to make the other actors better. It&#8217;s what you think of when you hear the term &#8220;actor&#8217;s actor&#8221;. It&#8217;s a joy to watch him work. And even more importantly, he&#8217;s damned funny. You probably remember him from X-MEN. He was Magneto&#8217;s father.</p>
<p>You don&#8217;t meet a whole lot of actors that make you want to write something for them specifically. He&#8217;s certainly one of them.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" title="meet the kids by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5605572025/"><img class="colorbox-5969"  src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5105/5605572025_53b2cee7e3_z.jpg" alt="meet the kids" width="500" height="281" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Filmmaker <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm2941069/">Lucas McNelly</a> is spending a year on the road, volunteering on indie film projects around the country, documenting the process and the exploring the idea of a mobile creative professional. You can see more from <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.ayearwithoutrent.com/">A Year Without Rent</a> at the webpage. Follow him on Twitter: <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #3778cd;" href="http://www.twitter.com/lmcnelly">@lmcnelly</a>.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p></span></div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-day-1-of-dave-bulliss-game-over/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guest Post: Prequel to Dave Bullis&#8217; GAME OVER</title>
		<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-prequel-to-dave-bullis-game-over/</link>
		<comments>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-prequel-to-dave-bullis-game-over/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2011 15:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Post]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/04/guest-post-prequel-to-dave-bullis-game-over/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[by Lucas McNelly&#160; A traveling tip from me to you: let&#8217;s say you have to get on a train that leaves at 7:20am and you&#8217;ve been up drinking until 4am. Find some Red Bull and just stay up. I know you think you&#8217;re very responsible and will surely get up in an hour or so, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="posterous_autopost">by Lucas McNelly&nbsp;</p>
<div>
<div style="color: #7f7f7f; font-family: Arial, Tahoma, Helvetica, FreeSans, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; line-height: 18px;">
<div class="post-body entry-content" style="line-height: 1.4;"><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #508bbe;" title="beta access by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5605568477/"><img class="colorbox-5830"  style="border-color: initial; border-style: none; padding: 8px;" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4099/5605568477_316d1ee471_z.jpg" alt="beta access" width="640" height="359" /></a>A traveling tip from me to you: let&#8217;s say you have to get on a train that leaves at 7:20am and you&#8217;ve been up drinking until 4am. Find some Red Bull and just stay up. I know you think you&#8217;re very responsible and will surely get up in an hour or so, but you won&#8217;t. You&#8217;ll end up waking up at 6:51am and panicking when you realize that you never did get around to packing the night before.</p>
<p><span id="more-5830"></span></p>
<p>Fun fact: did you know that depending on where you are in Pittsburgh, you can get from a dead sleep in an apartment to your seat on the train in 24 minutes? It&#8217;s true!</p>
<p>Anyway, the train took me to Philadelphia, where I managed to get in the wrong car before finally being whisked to Aston and Sun Center Studios, the location for Dave Bullis&#8217; GAME OVER.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #508bbe;" title="slate by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5605567369/"><img class="colorbox-5830"  style="border-color: initial; border-style: none; padding: 8px;" src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5068/5605567369_23f20ff007_z.jpg" alt="slate" width="640" height="359" /></a></p>
<p>GAME OVER is in name a TV pilot. The plan is to shoot this pilot episode and shop it around to networks and such. That&#8217;s Plan A in the sense that every indie film you work on would really like to get into Sundance or one of the bigger festivals. Of course, you&#8217;ve got to have a fallback plan in place. Theirs is to turn the show into a web series. A pretty reasonable Plan B, if you ask me.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t know a lot about the series going in, other than the fact that it&#8217;s about &#8220;the worst video game store in the world&#8221;. Off-topic, that&#8217;s more than I know about video games themselves. (But I will kick your ass on Mario Kart for the Super Nintendo. Don&#8217;t even try.)</p>
<p>I arrive the day before and they&#8217;re putting the finishing touches on the set. My first task is to take some magic markers and greek out video game cases in order to hide faces, logos, titles, basically anything that could get the production in legal trouble. There&#8217;s probably 200 of these that still need to be done, so there&#8217;s no way I&#8217;m going to finish in time. The plan is just to swap the finished ones around as needed.</p>
<p><a style="text-decoration: none; color: #508bbe;" title="funstation by lucas.mcnelly, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucasmcnelly/5606151848/"><img class="colorbox-5830"  style="border-color: initial; border-style: none; padding: 8px;" src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5303/5606151848_9268d792ec_z.jpg" alt="funstation" width="640" height="359" /></a></p>
<p>From there, it&#8217;s over to Neumann University (never heard of it? Me either) for a production meeting with the world-famous <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #508bbe;" href="http://www.twitter.com/Leah_Cevoli">Leah Cevoli</a>. It&#8217;s around that point that I realize I haven&#8217;t eaten all day. I&#8217;ve also had very little caffeine and no alcohol. This is Philadelphia. Shouldn&#8217;t they be handing out cheesesteaks when you get off the train?</p>
<p>I get easily distracted when I&#8217;m hungry and tired and holy shit, they have cases of Four Loko here. Must. Resist.</p>
<p>Where was I? Oh right. Tomorrow we start on GAME OVER. Call is 7am. Must sleep. But first, an actual conversation:</p>
<p>Dave Bullis: &#8220;Sorry my car&#8217;s a mess. I&#8217;ve kind of been living out of it lately.&#8221;<br />
Me: &#8220;That must be a hassle.&#8221;<br />
Dave Bullis: &#8220;Yeah&#8221; [beat] &#8220;Oh,&#8221; [Laughs] &#8220;I completely forgot who I was talking to.&#8221;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Filmmaker <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #508bbe;" href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm2941069/">Lucas McNelly</a> is spending a year on the road, volunteering on indie film projects around the country, documenting the process and the exploring the idea of a mobile creative professional. You can see more from <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #508bbe;" href="http://www.ayearwithoutrent.com/">A Year Without Rent</a> at the webpage. Follow him on Twitter: <a style="text-decoration: none; color: #508bbe;" href="http://www.twitter.com/lmcnelly">@lmcnelly</a>.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-prequel-to-dave-bullis-game-over/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guest Post: Get yourself into a situation where you don&#8217;t have a choice</title>
		<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-get-yourself-into-a-situation-where-you-dont-have-a-choice/</link>
		<comments>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-get-yourself-into-a-situation-where-you-dont-have-a-choice/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2011 16:01:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Post]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flywayfilmfestival.org/?p=5665</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Posted by Jayce Bartok &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; “get yourself into a situation where you don’t have a choice” So my wife and partner in crime, Tiffany, was listening to the latest brilliant podcast from Marc Maron on his awesome show WTF , featuring Conan O’Brien this week, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Posted by Jayce Bartok</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/wp-content/uploads/sites/5/2011/04/conan-o-brien+show+tbs.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-5666 colorbox-5665" title="conan-o-brien+show+tbs" src="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/wp-content/uploads/sites/5/2011/04/conan-o-brien+show+tbs.jpg" alt="" width="288" height="262" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>“get yourself into a situation where you don’t have a choice”</p>
<p><span id="more-5665"></span></p>
<p>So my wife and partner in crime, Tiffany, was listening to the latest<br />
brilliant podcast from Marc Maron on his awesome show WTF , featuring<br />
Conan O’Brien this week, and as we were drifting off to sleep mumbled<br />
to me, <em>“Get yourself into a situation where you don’t have a choice.”</em><br />
It’s a quote from Conan, whose dad passed it on to him. I sat staring<br />
at the ceiling for awhile thinking about the profundity (is that a<br />
word?) of this no choices advise.</p>
<p>Then it occurred to me that is what us indie filmmakers must do: get<br />
ourselves in a situation where we have to make our movie. Tiff and I<br />
talked about how we are accepting donations for Tiny Dancer from you<br />
generous people out there, and we are on the hook. We have to make<br />
this film. We have NO CHOICE.</p>
<p>So next month, we are shooting two days on the film with amazing people:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/wp-content/uploads/sites/5/2011/04/r19.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-5667 colorbox-5665" title="r19" src="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/wp-content/uploads/sites/5/2011/04/r19.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="400" srcset="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/wp-content/uploads/sites/5/2011/04/r19.jpg 300w, http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/wp-content/uploads/sites/5/2011/04/r19-225x300.jpg 225w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Tony and Spirit nominee, Daphne Rubin-Vega, DP Kate Phelan, and more<br />
to come…. We are doing it. It feels amazing to be beginning a<br />
mini-pre-production, the past few days flying by with scripts, crew,<br />
rentals, ideas, pictures, scouts, actors. Ah, Wilderness!<br />
Filmmaking…finally.</p>
<p>Let’s all get NO CHOICES.</p>
<p>We are fundraising for the film Tiny Dancer. By donating at<br />
<a href="http://www.theindependentcollective.com/">www.theindependentcollective.com</a> you become a member of TIC and help<br />
us acheive our goal of raising the film’s budget. Spreading the word,<br />
“following” and “liking” are free. And we like you too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/guest-post-get-yourself-into-a-situation-where-you-dont-have-a-choice/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
