<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>2014 FFF</title>
	<atom:link href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2014/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2014</link>
	<description>Just another Flyway Film Festival site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 20:47:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.8.6</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">75991295</site>	<item>
		<title>Nationally-Renowned Producer / Entrepreneur Nick Gonda to Speak at Kickoff Gala</title>
		<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2014/nationally-renowned-producer-entrepreneur-nick-gonda-to-speak-at-kickoff-gala/</link>
		<comments>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2014/nationally-renowned-producer-entrepreneur-nick-gonda-to-speak-at-kickoff-gala/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 16:43:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lu Lippold]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Event]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2014/?p=536</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Nicolas Gonda, who was recently named one of Variety’s “10 Producers to Watch,” Details Magazine’s “Digital Mavericks,” and Indiewire’s “Influencers,” will provide the keynote address at the Flyway&#8217;s Kickoff Gala on Thursday, October 23rd. Gonda co-founded Tugg, Inc., a rapidly-expanding web platform that enables audiences to choose the films that play in their local theaters. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2014/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2014/10/tugg-logo.png"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-538" src="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2014/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2014/10/tugg-logo.png" alt="tugg logo" width="128" height="91" /></a>Nicolas Gonda, who was recently named one of <em>Variety’</em>s “10 Producers to Watch,” <em>Details Magazine</em>’s “Digital Mavericks,” and <em>Indiewire’</em>s “Influencers,” will provide the keynote address at the Flyway&#8217;s Kickoff Gala on Thursday, October 23rd. Gonda co-founded <a href="http://www.tugg.com/">Tugg, Inc.</a>, a rapidly-expanding web platform that enables audiences to choose the films that play in their local theaters.</p>
<p>Gonda began his film career at Focus Features in New York City, working on the publicity, marketing, and worldwide distribution of a number of Academy Award® winning films such as THE PIANIST and ETERNAL SUNSHINE OF THE SPOTLESS MIND. In 2005, he joined the production of Terrence Malick’s THE NEW WORLD<em>,</em> and he went on to work with Malick as co-producer of THE TREE OF LIFE, Oscar™ nominee for Best Picture and winner of the Palme d’Or at the 2011 Cannes Film Festival, and producer of TO THE WONDER.</p>
<p>&#8220;Nick Gonda represents what the Flyway is all about: getting good films by independent filmmakers to audiences everywhere,&#8221; says Flyway Executive Director Rick Vaicius. &#8220;Our local audience will be excited to learn about Tugg as a way to bring more movies to this area, since we&#8217;re in a bit of a film desert in Western Wisconsin. Except for the new <a href="http://flywayminema.com/">Flyway Minema</a>, of course,&#8221; he adds. The Minema is a 40-seat microcinema in Pepin, recently started by Vaicius and his wife Diana.</p>
<p>Gonda continues to produce a number of projects with Malick, including A.J. Edwards&#8217; directorial debut <a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2014/film/the-better-angels/">THE BETTER ANGELS</a>, starring Diane Kruger, Jason Clarke and Brit Marling. THE BETTER ANGELS premiered at Sundance and will screen at the Flyway on Saturday, October 25th at 3:00 PM.</p>
<p>Following the keynote address, Vaicius will present the Festival “Axe” awards, designed by Wisconsin sculptor <a href="http://www.culverstudio.com/">David Culver</a>. Awardees will be announced in the categories of narrative, documentary, and Wisconsin/Minnesota films, as well as several special jury awards and the &#8220;Spirit of Flyway&#8221; award. The evening continues with music by the up-and-coming Minneapolis band <em><a href="http://sungodstogammarays.bandcamp.com/">Sun Gods to Gamma Rays</a></em>. Called “restrained, powerful, potent and cool” by <em>l’etoile Magazine</em>, the band’s &#8220;trippy, ethereal sounds will make you want to get up and dance” (<em>Minnesota Monthly</em>).</p>
<p>Everyone is welcome at this event. Tickets are <strong>$35 </strong>at <a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.com">flywayfilmfestival.com</a> or at the door, with food and drinks included in the ticket price. Full Festival Pass holders are admitted free.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2014/nationally-renowned-producer-entrepreneur-nick-gonda-to-speak-at-kickoff-gala/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">536</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
