<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>gala &#8211; 2011 FFF</title>
	<atom:link href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/tag/gala/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011</link>
	<description>The Best Indie Fest on Lake Pepin</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 00:02:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.8.6</generator>
	<item>
		<title>2011 2011 Flyway Film Festival Kickoff Gala</title>
		<link>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/2011-flyway-film-festival-kickoff-gala/</link>
		<comments>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/2011-flyway-film-festival-kickoff-gala/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 12:55:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gala]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[party]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://flywayfilmfestival.org/?p=14017</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Pepin, WI—The 4th Annual 2011 Flyway Film Festival announces the exclusive “Flyway Gala” opening night party and awards ceremony at the Lake Pepin Art &#38; Design Center, October 20, 2011. The Flyway Gala, an extravaganza of food, libations and entertainment, as well as the formal presentation of the Festival awards (designed by nationally recognized local [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<p>Pepin, WI—The 4<sup>th</sup> Annual 2011 Flyway Film Festival announces the exclusive “Flyway Gala” opening night party and awards ceremony at the Lake Pepin Art &amp; Design Center, October 20, 2011. The Flyway Gala, an extravaganza of food, libations and entertainment, as well as the formal presentation of the Festival awards (designed by nationally recognized local artist David Culver), is a must-attend event for film professionals, art and music aficionados and anyone who truly appreciates independent film.</p>
<p>Minneapolis’ film-friendly indie rockers <strong><em>Greycoats</em></strong>, described by Reveille Magazine as “dulcet anglophile pop,” will headline the party. The riotously melodic Greycoats have been steadily gaining national attention over the last few years, bolstered by their song “Watchmen, What Is Left of the Night,” featured on the second season of the CW’s popular series <em>Gossip Girl</em>.</p>
<p><a href="http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/2011-flyway-film-festival-kickoff-gala/"><em>Click here to view the embedded video.</em></a></p>
<p>The evening’s stellar musical line-up also features longtime Minneapolis music innovator, Christian Erickson <em>(Blue Sky Blackout </em>and<em> Astronaut Wife</em>), aka <strong><em>Byzantine Beatbox</em></strong><em>, </em>mixing infectious electronic drum grooves with medieval-tinged melodies. Erickson’s sweeping instrumental landscapes are as much visual as they are audio, with tracks synced and enhanced with evocative digitally-altered still images.</p>
<p>Full Festival pass holders, Opening Night ticket holders, and specially designated Festival guests and partners, including sponsors Joia All Natural Soda, Treasure Island Casino, Red Wing Framing, Lake Pepin Real Estate, and Cinematic, are invited to attend this VIP Gala. The evening will begin with a reception of small bites and hors d’oeuvres catered by local restaurateurs and food professionals, as well as signature Flyway cocktails, featuring mixologist-created Joia sodas, where attendees can network and mingle between 6:00 pm and 9:00 pm. It will be a great opportunity to meet and connect with directors, screenwriters and other professionals in the film industry, as well as the local community. This reception will be followed by an exclusive, private rock-and-roll show exclusive to Gala attendees.</p>
</div>
<p>Chicago artist and filmmaker Coleman Miller’s (<em>Uso Justo</em>) large-scale, looped 16mm film and digital video projection installation will be ongoing in the back courtyard/tent lounge area of the Art &amp; Design Center throughout the evening.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://blip.tv/play/AZ2rCAI.html?p=1" width="290" height="245" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe><embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://a.blip.tv/api.swf#AZ2rCAI" style="display:none"></embed></p>
<p>The Flyway Gala will kick off the official 2011 2011 Flyway Film Festival proceedings on the evening of Friday, October 21, with the opening night film taking place at WideSpot Performing Arts Center and a special late-night screening at the Lake Pepin Art &amp; Design Center. Saturday and Sunday programming will involve movie screenings at both venues and special Q&amp;As and panel events to be announced.</p>
<p>The 2011 2011 Flyway Film Festival keynote speaker is respected director/author Jon Reiss, named one of “10 Digital Directors to Watch” by <em>Daily Variety. </em>Reiss will present his widely-acclaimed two-day workshop. “Think Outside the Box Office,” focused on introducing participants to the world of hybrid distribution and marketing for filmmakers October 20–21. Featured 2011 attendees and panelists are being finalized and will be announced in the coming weeks.</p>
<div style="font-family: Helvetica, arial;"><a style="background: #2e9dc5 url('http://flywayfilmfestival.ticketleap.com/assets/images/bevel-bg.png') repeat-x center center; border: 1px solid #2e9dc5; text-shadow: 0 -1px #2e9dc5; font-size: 18px; -moz-border-radius: 4px; -webkit-border-radius: 4px; -moz-box-shadow: 0 2px 3px rgba(0, 0, 0, .3); -webkit-box-shadow: 0 2px 3px rgba(0, 0, 0, .3); display: inline-block; margin: 0; text-align: center; padding: 6px 10px 7px; text-decoration: none; font-weight: bold; color: #fff;" href="http://flywayfilmfestival.ticketleap.com/2011-flyway-film-festival-kickoff-gala/" target="_top">Buy Tickets</a></p>
<div style="font-size: 8pt; margin-top: 4px;"><a href="http://www.ticketleap.com/?rc=4bzyp1k">Online ticketing</a> with TicketLeap</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://flywayfilmfestival.org/2011/2011-flyway-film-festival-kickoff-gala/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
